Hi!
In our next segment, we'll be showing you mascara application.
The supplies that we're going to need for this is actually 2 disposable mascara wands, and we're also going to need our professional mascara.
The application of mascara can be very scary to makeup artist and scary to clients, so really reasuring them that we know what we're doing, we have a steady hand, and we have a great technique for applying mascara will help them feel at ease.
What we're going to do is we're going to take that mascara and remove the wand.
We're then going to dip our mascara wand just once in.
Now, if we were to go up, the traditional movement of going into mascara can actually cause clumping.
Just once in and once out will get plenty of product.
Next we're going to have our client look down.
By doing this action, not only do we have full response to the lashes here, but we can also make the client feel at ease because they're not seeing this wand going straight out their eyes.
I'm just going to briefly hold up just along the brow there.
Explain to your client that when we apply mascara in the salon or spa we can only do so much.
Sometimes at home they like to do their 20 coats or whatever.
We can certainly get a nice coverage.
She has beautiful lashes so that turned out perfect.
New wand.
We're just going to dip that right in.
Again, the client look down.
Perfect.
And our last step to the mascara application is going to be the curling of the lashes.
Again, you're going to have that client look down.
You notice by doing this after mascara application.
Yes, it is messy, but because we sanitize eyelash curler everytime, it's just fine.
What this does is it creates almost an extra hold like using hairspray on your hair and then curling it.
Same sort of effect you're going to get with using this after applying mascara.
Watch our next segment on appying cheek color.